Right, so this is just the breakdown, really, of the individual features of the characteristic of a price swing, individual components, okay, so one, two, three, four, equity base point, release, skinny leg.
And ultimately, this is the framework that price moves in, okay?
So, when we're looking at price, and when we're trying to find trades, okay, first of all, we're trading on the principles, right?
so prices seeking liquidity or it finds it liquidity is friction it has to move that
massive liquidity out of the way so you'll see your responses skinny legs or weak levels of
basically price runs that are running in a very inefficient skinny way they are getting
weaker and weaker and weaker and they're traveling and if they're then meeting a mass of
sell side on the opposite side of the market which is generally just a normal liquidity
waste what we have is a thick sell side base and a weak run a run that's getting
weaker or weaker you know that puts us in a manageable position to trade to the
weaker side of the market okay so that's another principal price goes to the
weaker side the same applies with extensions so you know this run is running
past highs extensions get filled so generally this leg will dry out and it
will draw back to the extension point okay but the important thing to realize here is
So when you're engaging for the first time,
over the first 10 time,
or for the first week, month, three months, quarter,
what you're gonna find is you're gonna be wrong, basically, right?
So you're going to pick a particular component
of a price from, which is let's say the liquidity base.
Okay, and what we expect at a liquidity base
is for price to come down, okay?
We want this kind of skinny leg extension into it,
because again, there's gonna be a massive liquidity
inside of the base, the core base.
And then the run that's coming into it, that slipping into it is a weak run.
It's a run that's getting weaker, weaker and weaker.
It's leaving thin levels of liquidity.
And of course, you know, they're going to yield the better responses, the more manageable responses.
We're looking for that.
But when you're first starting to exercise, okay, what you'll find is many, many times your liquidity base is wrong.
Okay?
That price just gives a small reaction and goes through it.
Okay.
And generally, the issue is, I wouldn't.
able to tell you why that liquidity base didn't work. It was just generally going to be higher
time frame context related. Okay, for example, this high just picked up a higher time frame level
and this is a residual level, middle of the price front, you know, you're just going to get small
responses. And in other words, sorry, in another example, if this was a weekly level, then
you're most, you're very, very, very likely to get a big response out of that weekly base.
so what's going to happen is when you're first exercising you're going to be wrong okay and it's
important to write through that continue doing it and the more you do it you're going to start building
parameters okay you'll then be able to identify the most preferable highly probable
um characteristics in how price should approach the level how price should respond
the parameters around how it should respond for it to maintain that favorable preferable
probability okay for that trade working out and this trade will simply be a
liquidity base retest okay or a swing retest of a liquidity base a pickup of
liquidity okay that's just one feature of the price run okay also it's important
to know that this is not definitive so there's gonna be times again when you're
exercising and even when you're trading live that price just goes straight
through the base okay it could be event driven it could be a mid-price run
level which is residual okay you could be trading a five-minute base against a four-hour
level against price so prices just picked up four-hour sell side and you were trying to use a
five-minute level okay it could be any of those instances and price will go straight through it
so this is never definitive these lines so you know if price is coming to pick up unfilled liquidity
the top was picked on the shelf and it goes in a round run it comes to the bottom of the shelf it
doesn't mean you're going to get a response okay our job is to identify the
most highly probable instances where we are going to get a response off the shelf
bottom in what instances what time frame is the shelf present you know the
principle is higher time frame cause more liquidity but as we go through the
series you're really going to be covering the individual components of a
price run or features of a price run so inside at this point one liquidity
base it's also important to know that inside of here you're
still going to have, on a lower time frame, more of a micro scale viewpoint when you're
looking at this, you're still going to have the characteristics of this whole price
run. For example, you're going to have price pauses inside. You're going to have shelves. You're
going to have the apex consolidation. We're going to have the shelf flip and you can have the
gap slips. You can have a core liquidity base there inside of the broader liquidity base.
So there's a benefit to us because if we can identify these individual components,
It tells us where prices in that price run, what is likely to happen, and really and truly so when you're exercising, you're not necessarily going to be exercising every component of the price room. You're going to pick one aspect, one feature, have some parameters around it, i.e. When are you going to take the trade? What needs to happen after the trade is taken? How should price extend into the level? Should it drift into the level? Should it absorb it, etc.? We're going to take one feature of the price run.
and build a model around that and build a sample set around that okay and that becomes your
trade you know in your arsenal of trades okay so this is the framework that we're applying okay
an example of a trade that i like for you know just for this for the purpose of recording
for exercising it could be when the price has extended okay has become inefficient it can
pause and then extend it efficiently into like a top side of a fractal so there's liquidity at the
bottom top and middle and top sorry and this last parabolic leg on the fractal my new scale can extend
to the top side of that fractal i'll go short there okay that puts me in a really manageable position
and then i'm expecting for this shelf that's holding the apex on that's holding price above the apex base
here for price to deal the remaining liquidity inside of the apex base, absorb it inside
where I just picked, where, you know, where I took an entry where I deemed it to be sell-side
and, you know, price then flip shelf and trends down. Okay. It ends up filling this leg into
a broader shelf and, you know, I'll probably look to take some equity down here and here.
But we'll cover taking equity and how we have to contend with price pauses when we're in the
short. What can happen? It can run.
pastels etc we'll cover that when we cover the price pores and the the the
mid flow part but point I'm making here is that is just one trade that I can
take and I like taking in the whole characteristic of a price run or price
swing or the anatomy of a price swing that's just one okay so when price is
putting in the high when I take that trade there's very very specific
you know parameters for what needs to happen prior to the entry taking the
entry it just becomes a unique set out to me and you're unique set up to my
understanding so this for example right you can have a shelf here pricing
validates the shelf and then it runs to new highs that'd be a perfect short from
okay we have had the see we have the inefficient extension okay even though
this is just a minute fractal extension in relation to this border price
wing okay and I like those really jumpy tops
especially after prices pause for a bit,
especially if it's dug really deep and invalidated to the shelf
and then it runs all the way higher again to fresh liquidity
and there's like a pool of liquidity here.
So the bottom side was picked and price runs the top.
You know, to me, they're just awesome trades.
But the point to note here is I still have all the individual components
that I like to take a trade on, i.e. the inefficient extension.
Shelf is weak.
The inventory of buyers is weakening.
prices at the high already anyway is already run so far okay um also like this shove the
broader shove the top side was picked there and the bottom and then it releases so this level is
you know very likely going to be washed up um once we picked up this short here or the south side
liquidity there really you know it it doesn't have to be a mass of sellers there it could be because
of how far prices run, buys are pushed and pushed and they pushed and they pushed, the weaker
they've got. The inventory of buy-side liquidity has now been weakened. We're now picking up. You
have to go really deep to find inventory. I have to go really deep to find inventory. When it was
here, inventory was very close, very close, very close, very close, very close, until it met some
sellers and then it formed a fractal head, picked up liquidity out of the broad shelf, and it went
another price run this is one price run inside of another price run okay so again it goes
back to my point saying you can have the the same features and the individual features and
characteristics of a price run inside the broader price run you can basically have smaller price
runs like that inside of a broader price run okay now that's just one example right so
ultimately during the series we're going to be covering shelf top
shelf bombs apex bases the gap slip so how price will accelerate once it breaks
beneath the shelf like this okay mid-flow so when prices just there's no bids
available there's no buyers there there's not enough buyers there they're just
not enough buyers there there's some buyers there but just not enough to
materially push price like this okay and ultimately you know what kind of
price behaviors and the characteristics we can expect during those times, okay, how they
relate to our trade management, okay, the apex, sorry, not the apex, the liquidity-based
retest, so the book is retest, how that would pick up its own liquidity, also the apex-based
retest, so price pumps, it comes back in towards the apex base, or the clean breaking
point where there's a pocket of liquidity there. Also it forms a shelf, you know, a bit of a
out there um why we will look to take those trades price doing it often real examples of
they're doing that um and then of course when price bleeds back into the core you know the
breakout accumulation there or the core liquidity base or the unfilled liquidity at the
bottom okay but yeah so during this kind of video during this series in a way i'll be
covering the individual components i'm explaining them showing real examples and really to
explain the individual components of the price room okay any questions that you know